# **Timothy Mickiewicz**

Nashville, TN 37211 | 731-439-6870 | Email: timothy.mickiewicz@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/timothymickiewicz1995">https://www.linkedin.com/in/timothymickiewicz1995</a>

Github: <a href="https://github.com/timothymickiewicz">https://github.com/timothymickiewicz</a> | Portfolio: <a href="https://timothymickiewicz.github.io/">https://timothymickiewicz.github.io/</a>

# Summary

Full-stack web developer with a professional background of 3 years in Analytical Science. Leverages critical thinking skills with prowess in a range of front and back end technologies to create smooth and well-rounded web applications. Adaptable, studious, and eager to go beyond what is required of any role. Bootcamp certified in the MERN stack as well as able to finesse a variety of open-source libraries to give a unique style and function to any application.

#### **Technical Skills**

CSS3, HTML5, JavaScript, jQuery, SQL, MongoDB, Java, Moment.js, Node.js, Bootstrap, Materialize, Semantic UI

# **Projects**

 $\textbf{Space} \mid \textbf{Github:} \underline{\textbf{https://github.com/timothymickiewicz/space}} \mid$ 

Live-Link: https://timothymickiewicz.github.io/space/

- An application that gets NASA information to display information based on user input. This application was created with an intent to be educational in nature.
- I designed the AJAX calls for the information to be displayed from, and built a dynamic and interactive carousel to display images from NASA's database. I assisted with all other aspects of the project and provided advice and snippets of code for my team.
- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Moment.js, Materialize, Semantic UI, AJAX

**WeatherDashboard** | Github: <a href="https://github.com/timothymickiewicz/WeatherDashboard">https://github.com/timothymickiewicz/WeatherDashboard</a> | Live-Link: <a href="https://timothymickiewicz.github.io/WeatherDashboard/">https://timothymickiewicz.github.io/WeatherDashboard/</a>

- An application to display the weather of any city that the user enters. Cities display: temperature (F), wind speed, UV index, and humidity as well as a 5 day forecast.
- Solo application.
- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ¡Query, Bootstrap, Moment.js

WorkDay | Github: <a href="https://github.com/timothymickiewicz/WorkDay">https://github.com/timothymickiewicz/WorkDay</a> |

Live-Link:https://timothymickiewicz.github.io/WorkDay/

- An application to plan your work day. Tasks move up the list until they are in the "late" zone. The user can add as many tasks as they want.
- Solo application.
- HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, Moment.js, Bootstrap

# Experience

**Analytical Chemist** – Aegis Sciences Corporation

Nashville, TN

July 2018 – Present

- Gained Experience with LC and GC Mass spectrometers, scripted automated batch building/extraction EVOware, acid/base chemistry, and various types of lab software (reporting, quantifying data, sample tracking, storage, etc.)
- Passed training to be a Certifier of lab testing results

Cross-trained into all departments inside of the lab to become fully flexible

# **Forensic Evidence Processing Technician** – Aegis Sciences Corporation Nashville. TN

October 2017 – July 2018

- Gained experience with sample tracking software, sample receiving software, and databases
- Acquired intermediate skill with Excel, Word, Outlook, and OneNote for contacting various departments, building tables from database data, and presenting work flows to the department
- Awarded 3 WE3 company awards for teamwork and work effort

#### Education

**Full-Stack Web Development Certificate** – Trilogy Education Services via Vanderbilt University

January 2020 – Current

- Acquired skill with front-end and back-end technologies that are involved with full web application development
- Gained experience with open-source libraries such as Bootstrap and jQuery
- Fully developed 3 web applications in coordination with a team of full-stack developers

### **Bachelor of Science** – Freed-Hardeman University

August 2013- May 2017

- Focus on biological sciences with over 24 hours of Chemistry/Math courses
- Involved with two research projects involving combined aspects of herpetology and microbiology
- Conducted international research in Costa Rica to monitor ecological impact of tourism/societal progression

#### **Electronics Testing Certificate** – Tennessee Technology Center

December 2016 – May 2017

- Learned to troubleshoot series and parallel circuits
- Gained experience with various components of a circuit board (resistors, transformers, relays, etc.)
- Acquired intermediate skill with a multimeter for the purpose of troubleshooting electrical components